LAYLA HASHMI

Full-Stack Software Engineer

CONTACT

- laylawaseem@gmail.com
 - 346-831-9036
 - Dallas, Tx
- linkedin.com/layla-hashmi/ in
 - Layla's Portfolio Website

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Software Engineer with 2 years of experience writing and testing code, helping develop software system solutions and updating companies' knowledge using the latest development tools. Well-skilled in software development life cycle, including requirement analysis, design, development and production support with a focus on clean coding practices and user-friendliness.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

Biology; Minor- Computer Science University of Texas - Arlington

Advanced Software Engineering Immersive Program

Hack Reactor Aug 2022 - May 2023 Austin, Tx

SKILLS

Language & Front End/Back End

Python (Django, FastAPI) JavaScript (ES6, React, Redux, Node.js) Typescript HTML/ CSS Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap

System Design

CI/CD, Docker, Git
Cloud (AWS)
REST APIs, Monoliths, Microservices
Object Oriented Programming
Domain Driven Design
Message Passing and Event sourcing
Pollers (RabbitMQ)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Tracer Labs

January 2023 - current / Remote

- Led architecture, design, and development of 20+ new features following common security practices and development design patterns
- Built 100+ unit tests to verify the functionality of user interfaces, back-end processing, connectivity, and relational database interactions
- Engaged in requirements analysis, High Level Design, Low Level Design, and complex code development for 10+ applications.
- Cultivated action mindset in ever-changing project priorities and adapted to various requirements to deliver high-quality solutions in the company's best interests.

Software Developer

Robinhood

February 2022 - January 2023 / Westlake, Tx

- Assisted in developing a CRM software upgrade (Salesforce) that contributed to cost savings and improved customer service by 73%
- Tested software for bugs and operating speed, fixing bugs and documenting processes to increase efficiency by 18%
- Collaborated with a team of developers to implement RESTful APIs in Django, enabling analytics team to increase reporting speed by 24%
- Brainstormed and implement ideas and feedback into app's development
- Selected as the top performing developer by the technology team

PROJECTS

Tripper

Lead Full-Stack Software Engineer May 2023

- Managed a 5-member team through the development pipeline for the project, from ideation to testing and deployment, using Agile and Scrum methodologies to deliver project on time.
- Developed RESTful API routes to make a CRUD application which allows a user to track and plan a trip by adding, deleting, updating and viewing all details of a trip
- Implemented authorization and authentication using JWT and MongoDB for efficient data retrieval
- Designed the user interface using Tailwind and CSS to optimize the user experience

AutoScape

Full-Stack Software Engineer Apr 2023

- Developed a single-page application to manage various aspects of an automobile dealership to maintain organized records, boosting business efficiency by 70%
- Implemented form submission for client-side appointment scheduling and search/filter components to enhance user experience, increasing website traffic by 68%
- Integrated RESTful APIs into separation sales and service microservices with PostgresQL, maintaining user authentication and client information security